

■ me@cheukwing.dev | 😭 cheukwing | 🛅 cheukwing

## Summary\_

Final year Imperial College student with a range of experiences in computer science from education, industry, and the wider community - including contributions to open source, teaching to young students, and development of applications from idea to product.

Has a particular interest in distributed systems and functional programming.

## Education \_\_\_\_

### **Imperial College London**

London

MENG IN COMPUTING (PREDICTED FIRST CLASS)

Oct 2016 - Jun 2020

- Modules include: 81% Type Systems, 81% Distributed Algorithms, 79% Information and Coding Theory.
- Engineering **Dean's List** for top 10% performance in second year.
- Won Morgan Stanley Prize for top 12 first year students.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Jetstack** Londor

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Apr 2019 - Sep 2019

- Completely rewrote the frontend of Flightdeck (a web application for Kubernetes training) to Elm best practices, facilitating and subsequently supporting the onboarding of a new frontend engineer.
- Contributed to Cert-Manager, the open source Kubernetes project for managing TLS certificates, becoming the 5th top contributor at the time.
- Co-led the design and implementation of a platform for the provisioning of arbitrary environments to host *Flightdeck* training scenarios upon, building **Kubernetes controllers** in **Go** and making thorough use of **Docker** and **Google Cloud**, cutting the running cost of the application versus the existing third party service.
- · Participated in fortnightly sprint planning, sprint retrospectives, and daily stand-ups, gaining industrial experience of Agile development.

Ocado Technology Hatfield

TECHNOLOGY INTERN

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Connected together several pieces of sensor hardware with several **computer vision** libraries to develop a single **C++** library with which to track the real time movements of a person.
- Developed the library into an **Electron** application, transmitting and mapping the movements to a remote, life-size, robotic upper body to make video conferencing more engaging and interactive.

# Projects\_\_\_\_\_

### **Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA)**

https://ait.io/Je0bK

THIRD YEAR GROUP PROJECT

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

- As a group, developed a rule-based NLP solution for the extraction and storage of entity-attribute pairs with their calculated sentiment from
  news articles using **Python**, streamlining the work of a financial analyst by providing easy access to aggregated sentiment and relevant
  quotations for companies of interest.
- Further showcased the use of the solution by building a demo application with a **RESTful**, **Python** backend and **React** frontend.

**Lembas** Available on Request

WEBAPPS GROUP PROJECT

lun 2019

- In a group, developed a full stack **React/Node/PostgreSQL** web application for the creation and sharing of meal plans, helping to combat the issue of unbalanced diets by providing a method of communication between nutritionists and everyday people.
- Implemented human-centered-design techniques including user stories and micro-iterations from demoing and surveying potential users, ensuring all committed changes were improvements to the user experience.

## Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_\_\_

### Imperial College London (Department of Computing)

Londo

PERSONAL PROGRAMMING TUTOR

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019

- Ran a weekly tutorial with a group first-year students to supplement their Haskell and Java learning, expanding their knowledge of algorithms
  and helping them to follow good software design practices.
- · Marked and gave feedback to weekly assignments, highlighting mistakes and ways to improve.

Robogals London

Training Manager Apr 2017 - Apr 2018

- Regularly volunteered to teach classes of schoolchildren in workshops to program Lego robots, introducing them to the basics of programming.
- Prepared and led training days to on-board new volunteers, simultaneously also introducing many to programming as well.
- Designed new workshops and teaching materials, introducing the use of variables and techniques of iterative design, which helped to attract
  more enthusiasm from classes of older schoolchildren and increased the range of skills taught by the society.